on line one we can see an array
that contains three names and three
numbers
alternating the problem description
asks us without writing any additional
code
to group each name with the number
following it
in its own array and each of these
smaller
two element arrays will be nested in
this larger array
so let's see what this would look like
you can see that we've now got three two
element
arrays within this outer array
so the outer array has three elements
each of which are arrays and these three
inner arrays each have two elements one
string and one integer
the important thing to realize here with
this exercise
is that arrays can contain any object
here we see an array that contains other
arrays
and we call this a nested array
let's take a moment to think about how
we would
access the elements of these inner
arrays
for example let's say we want to access
the number 7
which is the second element in our first
nested array
let's call this array list
and using element reference we can
access that
first nested array at index 0.
and let's output this just to see that
so we're successfully accessing that
first nested array
which is the first element of our list
array
using element reference now how can we
access the elements within this nested
array
recall that element reference is
actually an array method
and we can chain method calls so the
element reference we currently have on
line 3 returns the nested array at
index 0. by chaining
an additional element reference onto
this first method call we are
invoking the second element reference on
the returned array
we've specified that we want to access
the element at index 1
of the subarray so we expect that we'll
be outputting the integer 7.
and we do